### **Nathan Underwood**

Garden Grove, CA

Email: <a href="mailto:nathannunderwood@gmail.com">nathannunderwood@gmail.com</a> | Github: <a href="mailto:https://github.com/thundernunder">https://github.com/thundernunder</a>

**LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathanunderwood20/ **Portfolio**: https://thundernunder.github.io/20-React-Portfolio/

#### **Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer with a Marketing background and 6 years of experience as Director of Admissions Marketing at Mater Dei High School in Santa Ana, CA. Excited to build/maintain seamless web and mobile applications and utilize expert communication, collaboration, and marketing analytic skills from previous experience. Known by my coworkers as a fierce competitor who stays calm and cool under pressure and can keep things light in the workplace.

#### **Tools and Skills**

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript

**Applications:** NodeJS, Express, Insomnia, SQL and MySQL Workbench, NoSQL (MongoDB and Mongoose ODM), Progressive Web Applications (Babel, Webpack, etc...), React, MERN Stack (Apollo, JSON Web Tokens, etc...)

**Tools:** Web APIs, Third Party APIs (Bootstrap, jQuery, Moment, Google Fonts, etc...), Server-Side APIs, Object Oriented Programming, Object Relational Mapping, Model-View-Controller, Complex State Management, Git, Github/Github Pages, Heroku

#### **Projects**

**Breakhub** | <a href="https://github.com/aurorayihe/BreakHub\_theThunderCats">https://github.com/aurorayihe/BreakHub\_theThunderCats</a> https://aurorayihe.github.io/BreakHub\_theThunderCats/

- Description: A customized virtual break room for killing time efficiently. Whether you are
  a working professional, student, or want to keep on task for things around the house,
  BreakHub gives you the break you need and gets you back on task when the time is right.
- My Responsibilities: Development of "random facts" feature, README, and overall project idea
- **Technologies Used:** HTML, CSS, Javascript, Web APIs (Giphy, The Cat API), Bulma CSS Framework

**GOAT Cars** | https://github.com/Young-Chhay/GOAT-CARs | https://limitless-inlet-80360.herokuapp.com/

 Description: A social media platform for classic car enthusiasts. Users create profiles to display images of classic cars they own, while also interacting with other users on the platform through following, liking, and commenting on user-to-user content.

- My Responsibilities: Development of Merchandise section, server.js, README, and overall project idea
- **Technologies Used:** HTML, CSS (Bulma), Javascript, Express, Express Handlebars, Express Session, Sequelize, MySQL2, Socket.io

## **Play2Day |** https://github.com/Young-Chhay/Play2Day | https://gentle-fortress-88764.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Whether it's to keep a competitive edge, stay in shape, or connect with
  friends, many people love playing sports recreationally, even if they can't play
  professionally. The problem is there are not many options focused on helping people
  organize pickup games in an easy way. Play2Day aims to fill this need by creating a space
  where users can connect with friends and members of their community by easily
  organizing pickup sports games. Get out there and Play2Day!
- My Responsibilities: Development of Models, Profile page, and AllGamesList component. Contributed to React implementation, connecting front-end to GraphQL,, and deployment to Heroku
- Technologies Used: GraphQL, Apollo Server Express, JSON Web Token, MongoDB, mongoose, Bcrypt, Express, Concurrently, React Bootstrap

#### **Experience**

# Director of Admissions Marketing – Mater Dei High School Santa Ana, CA

#### July 2016 – Present

Progressed through a variety of roles to current position of leading the school's admissions marketing efforts. Working for an institution with a 75+ year history allowed for modernizing marketing efforts in the following ways:

- Optimize admissions marketing calendar to create competitive advantage over rival schools for potential families, achieving high benchmarks of 1,400+ tour/shadow requests and 1,000+ total applicants on yearly-basis
- Manage \$70,000 budget that utilizes marketing tactics in ways not limited to: geofencing/data mining, website retargeting, digital advertising, social media, email/text, events, and print.
- Maintain admissions database of 10,000+ records
- Supervise Digital Marketing Internship program that hires six college-level interns annually in areas of Graphic Design, Photography, and Videography to cover school programs
- Expand potential reach of recruitment and improved customer service experience through collaboration with GoKid carpooling and PeerPal instant chat service
- Coordinate 10+ targeted admissions events of varying scales, from Open House events of 1000+ attendees to localized events in individual neighborhoods

#### **Development Assistant – Long Beach State University Athletics**

#### Long Beach, CA

#### **July 2015 – July 2016**

Responsibilities in this role were to support the Assistant Director of Athletics in reaching annual fundraising goals. Some accomplishments include:

- Direct first Beach Athletic Club Membership Challenge resulting in increased membership of over 150 and raising over \$25,000 in six weeks
- Fundraise over \$60,000 for Annual Fund through the 49er Phone-A-Thon
- Execute three golf tournament fundraisers that generated over \$60,000 in revenue

#### Coordinator/Partnership Services – Learfield Sports Long Beach, California January 2016 – July 2016

Primary responsibilities in this role were to procure sponsorship partnerships for Long Beach State University Athletics. Once contractual relationships were established, I maintained communication with partners and oversaw the fulfillment of contracts between the university and sponsor. Accomplishments include:

- Secure three new sponsorship contracts never in association with Long Beach State
- Zero contracts breached during tenure with Learfield Sports

#### **Education**

#### The Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp at University of California - Irvine

Certificate

Expected Completion: December 19, 2022

#### **California State University, Long Beach**

Bachelor of Science Degree, Business Administration – Marketing

Graduated: May 2014

#### California State University, Long Beach

Master of Arts in Kinesiology: Emphasis in Sports Management

Graduated: July 2016